<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
  "../dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="logger-plugin" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Logger Plugin</title>
  <shortdesc>
    The Logger plugins helps with debugging during the process of sending.  It can
    help to identify why an SMTP server is rejecting addresses, or any other
    hard-to-find problems that may arise.
  </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <author type="creator">Chris Corbyn</author>
    <copyright>
      <copyryear year="2009"/>
      <copyrholder>Chris Corbyn</copyrholder>
    </copyright>
    <critdates>
      <created date="2009-February-16"/>
      <revised modified="2009-February-16"/>
    </critdates>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>swift mailer</keyword>
        <keyword>php</keyword>
        <keyword>plugins</keyword>
        <keyword>logger plugin</keyword>
        <indexterm>
          plugins
          <indexterm>logger plugin</indexterm>
        </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <p>
      The Logger plugin comes in two parts.  There's the plugin itself, along with
      one of a number of possible Loggers that you may choose to use.  For example,
      the logger may output messages directly in realtime, or it may capture messages
      in an array.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      One other notable feature is the way in which the Logger plugin changes Exception
      messages.  If Exceptions are being thrown but the error message does not provide
      conclusive information as to the source of the problem (such as an ambiguous
      SMTP error) the Logger plugin includes the entire SMTP transcript in the error
      message so that debugging becomes a simpler task.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      There are a few available Loggers included with Swift Mailer, but writing
      your own implementation is incredibly simple and is achieved by creating a
      short class that implements the <codeph>Swift_Plugins_Logger</codeph> interface.
    </p>
    
    <simpletable>
    
      <sthead>
        <stentry>Logger Class</stentry>
        <stentry>Description</stentry>
      </sthead>
    
      <strow>
       <stentry><codeph>Swift_Plugins_Loggers_ArrayLogger</codeph></stentry>
       <stentry>Keeps a collection of log messages inside an array.  The array content can be cleared or dumped out to the screen.</stentry>
      </strow>
    
      <strow>
       <stentry><codeph>Swift_Plugins_Loggers_EchoLogger</codeph></stentry>
       <stentry>Prints output to the screen in realtime. Handy for very rudimentary debug output.</stentry>
      </strow>
    
    </simpletable>
  </conbody>
</concept>
