<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
  "../dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="attachments" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Attaching Files</title>
  <shortdesc>
    Attachments are downloadable parts of a message and can be added by calling the
    attach() method on the message.  You can add attachments that exist on disk, or
    you can create attachments on-the-fly.
  </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <author type="creator">Chris Corbyn</author>
    <copyright>
      <copyryear year="2008"/>
      <copyrholder>Chris Corbyn</copyrholder>
    </copyright>
    <critdates>
      <created date="2008-December-26"/>
      <revised modified="2008-December-26"/>
    </critdates>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>swift mailer</keyword>
        <keyword>php</keyword>
        <keyword>message</keyword>
        <keyword>attachments</keyword>
        <indexterm>
          messages
          <indexterm>attachments</indexterm>
        </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <p>
      Attachments are actually an interesting area of Swift Mailer and something that
      could put a lot of power at your fingertips if you grasp the concept behind the
      way a message is held together.
    </p>
    <p>
      Although we refer to files sent over e-mails as "attachments" &#8211; because they're
      attached to the message &#8211; lots of other parts of the message are actually
      "attached" even if we don't refer to these parts as attachments.  We'll cover the obvious
      grounds of attaching files to a message first for those who just want to know how it's done,
      then we'll go on to discuss what I mean by other parts of the message being attachments for
      those who are interested in learning more.
    </p>
    <p>
      Attachments (in the normal file sense) are created by the <codeph>Swift_Attachment</codeph>
      class and then attached to the message via the <codeph>attach()</codeph> method on it.  For all
      of the "every day" MIME types such as all image formats, word documents, PDFs and spreadsheets
      you don't need to explicitly set the content-type of the attachment, though it would do no
      harm to do so.  For less common formats you should set the content-type &#8211; which we'll cover in a
      moment.
    </p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
