<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
  "../../dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="history" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>History of Swift Mailer</title>
  <shortdesc>
    Swift Mailer began back in 2005 as a one-class project for sending mail over SMTP.  It has since grown
    into the flexible component-based library that is in development today.
  </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <author type="creator">Chris Corbyn</author>
    <copyright>
      <copyryear year="2008"/>
      <copyrholder>Chris Corbyn</copyrholder>
    </copyright>
    <critdates>
      <created date="2009-January-02"/>
      <revised modified="2009-January-02"/>
    </critdates>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>swift mailer</keyword>
        <keyword>php</keyword>
        <keyword>code samples</keyword>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <p>
      I first posted Swift Mailer on a web forum at <xref href="http://forums.devnetwork.net" format="html" />
      asking for comments from other developers.  It was never intended as a fully supported open source
      project, but members of the forum began to adopt it and make use of it.
    </p>
    <p>
      Very quickly feature requests were coming to me for the ability to add attachments and use SMTP authentication,
      along with a number of other "obvious" missing features.  Considering the only alternative was PHPMailer it seemed
      like a good time to bring some fresh tools to the table.  I began working towards a more component based, PHP5-like
      approach unlike the existing single-class, legacy PHP4 approach taken by PHPMailer.
    </p>
    <p>
      Members of the forum offered a lot of advice and critique on my code as I worked through this project and released
      versions 2 and 3 of the library in 2005 and 2006, which by then had been broken down into smaller classes offering
      more flexibility and supporting plugins.  To this day I still receive a lot of feature requests from users both on the
      forum and in my inbox.
    </p>
    <p>
      I have learned a lot over the years whilst working on Swift Mailer and I believe that I have matured a lot as a developer,
      improving the underlying code in the library as I have done so.
    </p>
    <p>
      Until 2008 I was the sole developer of Swift Mailer, but entering 2009 I gained the support of two experienced
      developers well-known to me: Paul Annesley and Christopher Thompson.  This has been an extremely welcome change.
    </p>
    <p>
      Now 2009 and in its fourth major version Swift Mailer is more object-oriented and flexible than over, both from a usability
      standpoint and from a development standpoint.
    </p>
    <p>
      By no means is Swift Mailer ready to call "finished".  There are still many features that can be added to the library
      along with the constant refactoring that happens behind the scenes.
    </p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
