<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
  "../../../dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="mime" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>MIME Entities</title>
  <shortdesc>
    Everything that forms part of a Message is called a MIME Entity.  All MIME entities
    in Swift Mailer share a common set of features.  There are various types of MIME entity
    that serve different purposes such as Attachments and MIME parts.
  </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <author type="creator">Chris Corbyn</author>
    <copyright>
      <copyryear year="2008"/>
      <copyrholder>Chris Corbyn</copyrholder>
    </copyright>
    <critdates>
      <created date="2008-December-24"/>
      <revised modified="2008-December-24"/>
    </critdates>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>swift mailer</keyword>
        <keyword>php</keyword>
        <keyword>mime entity</keyword>
        <keyword>message</keyword>
        <keyword>mime part</keyword>
        <keyword>attachment</keyword>
        <keyword>embedded file</keyword>
        <keyword>image</keyword>
        <indexterm>
          mime entities
          <indexterm>messages</indexterm>
          <indexterm>mime parts</indexterm>
          <indexterm>attachments</indexterm>
          <indexterm>embedded files</indexterm>
          <indexterm>inline images</indexterm>
        </indexterm>
      </keywords>
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <p>
      An e-mail message is made up of several relatively simple entities that are combined in
      different ways to achieve different results.  All of these entities have the same fundamental
      outline but serve a different purpose.  The Message itself can be defined as a MIME entity,
      an Attachment is a MIME entity, all MIME parts are MIME entities &#8211; and so on&#8230;
    </p>
    <p>
      The basic units of each MIME entity &#8211; be it the Message itself, or an Attachment &#8211;
      are its Headers and its body:
      
<codeblock>Header-Name: A header value
Other-Header: Another value

The body content itself</codeblock>
      
    </p>
    <p>
      The Headers of a MIME entity, and its body must conform to some strict standards defined by
      various RFC documents.  Swift Mailer ensures that these specifications are followed by using
      various types of object, including Encoders and different Header types to generate the entity.
    </p>
    <p>
      Each MIME component implements the base <codeph>Swift_Mime_MimeEntity</codeph> interface, which
      offers methods for retrieving Headers, adding new Headers, changing the Encoder, updating
      the body and so on&#8230;
    </p>
    <p>
      All MIME entities have one Header in common &#8211; the Content-Type Header, updated with
      the entity's <codeph>setContentType()</codeph> method.
    </p>
  </conbody>
</concept>
